# Yanir Kleiman - Resume

Mobile: **+972 52 3343394** Website: **www.yanirk.com** 

Email Address: yanirk@gmail.com

I am a computer science PhD student in the Computer Graphics lab at Tel Aviv University.

My previous experience spans two years of professional experience as a 3D artist working on various visual effects and animation projects, and over 10 years experience in software development as programmer and team leader in several organizations.

# **Education**

2011 - ???	<b>PhD Student, Computer Science</b> , Tel Aviv University, Israel. Computer graphics lab, under the supervision of Prof. Daniel Cohen-Or.
2008 - 2009	<b>3D Animation and Visual Effects Diploma</b> , Vancouver Film School, Canada. Visual Effects specialization, graduated with honors.
2003 - 2005	<b>M.Sc. in Computer Science</b> , Tel Aviv Academic College, Israel Graduated with honors. Published a paper in Theoretical Computer Science journal, in the subject of online algorithms.
1997 - 2000	B.Sc. in Math and Computer Science, Tel Aviv University, Israel

#### **Awards and Publications**

2011	Unsupervised co-segmentation of a set of shapes via descriptor-space spectral
	clustering.
	Oana Sidi, Oliver van Kaick, Yanir Kleiman, Hao Zhang, Daniel Cohen-Or.
	ACM Transactions on Graphics (TOG) 30.6 (2011): 126

2010 Animex International Festival of Animation & Computer Games

Visual Effects Award runner up for my VFS graduation film.

2007 **Paging with connections: FIFO strikes again.**Leah Epstein, Yanir Kleiman, Jiri Sgall, Rob van Stee.

Theoretical computer science 377.1 (2007): 55-64

# **Professional Experience**

2010 Lighting and Rendering TD / Compositor, Crew 972

Worked on "The Looney Tunes Show" for Warner Bros.

- Lighting shots in Maya.
- Set dressing of shots in Maya.
- Creating special visual effects (dust, smoke) using dynamics and MEL scripting in Maya.
- Creating render layers and monitoring the render process on a render farm.
- MEL scripting for automated tasks in Maya.
- Final compositing of shots using Nuke.
- Working with "Shotgun" production tracking system.

**3D Artist, Gravity Israel Visual Effects** 

Worked mostly on shading, lighting, and render passes. Additional work included modeling and scripting.

# 2009 Freelance Effects Artist, "Deus".

"Deus" is a sci-fi TV show in Israel.

I created visual effects for several shots on the show from start to finish. Tracking, modeling, simulation, animation, rendering and compositing.

#### 2008 Algorithms Developer, MutualArt Inc.

Developed and implemented automated text categorization and linking algorithms with C# and SQL Server.

### 2005 - 2007 **Development Team Leader, Amobee Media Systems Ltd.**

The start-up company provides a platform for cellular advertising on multiple channels such as in-game advertising, WAP, SMS, MMS and streaming.

My team developed a web based back-office system that enables advertisers to manage their campaigns and creative ads.

- .NET infrastructures (ASP.NET) and SQL Server 2005 development.
- Management and task planning.
- Requirements specification.
- GUI design (flow and graphic design).
- Recruiting and training.
- Java development.

#### 2004 - 2005 **Development Team Leader, IDF.**

Team leader of about 7 programmers. The team supplied all internal computing needs of the unit.

The team developed and maintained about 10 different systems, some built with .NET infrastructures and some with Microsoft DNA infrastructures.

#### 2000 - 2004 **Senior Infrastructure Programmer, IDF.**

Lead the team migration process from DNA infrastructures to .NET infrastructures.

- Designed and implemented .NET infrastructures.
- Lead development of several .NET systems.
- Trained team members.
- Graphic design for all of the unit's web (intra-net) systems.

#### 1996 - 2000 Part Time VB and ASP Programmer, NTR Visual Technologies Ltd.

During my studies, I worked part time as a Visual Basic and ASP programmer.

## **Professional Skills**

### **CG Software:**

Maya, XSI, Mental Ray, Nuke, After Effects, Premiere, Photoshop, Boujou.

#### **Programming Languages and Technologies:**

C, C++, C#, VB.NET, Java, Matlab, JavaScript, VBScript, MEL and Python Scripting .NET Framework, ASP.NET, HTML, SQL Server, Oracle, XML, XSL, CSS

#### **Personal Details**

D.O.B: April 7, 1980.

Languages: **Hebrew** - mother tongue, **English** - excellent.

Yanir Kleiman Mobile: +972 52 3343394 Website: www.yanirk.com Email Address: yanirk@gmail.com